so uh our first lightning talk is from
Pine Mohan and he's going to do a demo
on using llms to extract filters for
your queries
yeah I'm thank you yeah hello everyone
so this is from our yesterday's talk
where we said Illustrated a process of
using large language
models uh to break down your query and
apply possible filters so that you can
better understand your users query so uh
you can see this was a slide that we
shown yesterday so say like you have a
query brown leather shoes forment under
50 you have your large language model
where you going to prompt your large
language model with the original index
uh mapping and then as and and and then
ask the large large language model okay
this is a query this is the index
mapping try to apply the filters
accordingly and then large language
model is going to give that structured
query that you see here with all the
comparison and The Logical operators and
finally on the application site I write
my rules to convert it into a open
search query DSL okay so this the third
piece could be changed with your domain
specific language based upon your engine
so let's see how this works uh on a demo
yeah okay so let me zoom in a bit Yeah
so this is the application that we have
built for demo purposes and and if you
recall from our yesterday session I we
said like if you have if you use open
search in just pipelines and uh search
pipelines like you can you don't have to
keep to have the any compents in the
middle like for example you have your
Search application and you have your say
a Lambda or any ec2 server to do all
those model transactions so with these
inest pipelines and search pipelines you
have your application integrated
directly with open search so I have I I
don't have anything in the middle so
it's like the ec2 instance acting as a
web server and it's contacting the
machine learning models backed by open
search okay so we'll start with the
basic uh lexical search without any uh
filter extraction from the large
language model we have this query black
jacket for in under $120 you see like
there are a lot of filters
here I'm doing a lexical search with
open
search uh and as you see this is uh
these are my results and this is my
document metadata where I have some
things already indexed as a part of
every document and you see the color I
was asking for black uh that's not
respected here and uh also if you see
the price of uh uh the black jacket like
it's over $120 I was asking for less
than
$120 yeah and also I have a irrelevant
uh result because of uh some keywords
but yeah this is another another
limitation of lexical search right yeah
so as you see most of my filters are not
respected mainly because I'm just doing
a match against the description of the
product and uh which means I'm not able
to understand all these filters which is
like present implicit in the inside the
query itself right so now let's do this
autop playay filters and this autoplay
filters is going to use llm at the back
end to uh generate filters on fly and
then apply that on the query okay so now
I got it uh uh I got the llm extracted
filters first let's see the query what's
happened to the query okay first thing I
say okay there is a compound query here
bull Boolean class and then I have a
should which says color as black it's
like an R condition right and then I
have some strict filters under must
class telling categories parallel gender
should be male and style should be
jacket and importantly you see this
price lesser than
120 right so this is something uh again
coming from my uh query where I said $1
$120 right this is all generated by the
large language model and uh let's see
the result
now yeah so I got different set of
results and you see the price is under
120 I have the gender is uh uh the
gender as a filter which is male and you
see this additional enrich attributes
this is what yesterday we covered in
terms of first if you want to do better
query understanding first you have first
you need to have a document Ed with
possible metadata so this is where like
these documents are Ed with like
possible metadata and here the color is
something added which we enriched using
image recognition model and that happens
to in just pipelines automatically yeah
so because of this enrich document
enrich attributes we are now able to do
matching better and most of the filters
are
respected here uh and yeah looks almost
better than the previous set of results
and but one thing here I still see this
color is not matching so let me go here
and then add color as should also be a
strict filter like I have already some
set of fields which should be strict
filter this is where I said like you
write your own business tools to convert
your uh to convert the structured query
from large language model into a domain
specific language query so you know what
is should be the strict and what could
be relaxed filter right and then uh now
having color also as the strict filter
inside the must
class yeah like uh this doesn't have
this llm cache at the screen okay so now
you see like almost everything the color
is also uh uh filtered for black right
so this is a way you can think about
using large language models to extract
filters and this not only applies for
lexical search for example I can also do
Vector search the same set of filters
applied so that Vector search is going
to improve your recall but you but you
still have your metadata filter strictly
applied so now I'm doing a vector
search and for this Vector search again
I got set of results but all the results
will have my filters respected totally
without these filters if you just do a
vector search you will get all
everything relevant but not with
respected filters right so that that is
where like these filters play critical
role to understand uses better
irrespective of the search you
do yeah so yeah this is something and
also you can and yesterday we covered
about different search types maybe
quickly I can show you how uh different
search types apply uh for example you
can do a hybrid search again through
that search Pipeline with hybrid hybrid
uh search
Pipeline and this is how the index looks
at the back
end we have this one in pipeline ml in
pipeline
and we have different processes with
different model IDs we have text
embedding text image embedding and spars
encoding processes so when you s a
document different vectors are generated
and stored in different fields so that
it facilitates with one index you can do
multiple types of searches yeah thank
you very
muchy adventures with a
n hi can you hear me well yep cool uh my
name is anus and today I'm going to very
quickly present some Adventures uh with
approximate nearest neighbors NN stands
for for approximate nearest
neighbors
um okay so on the slide that that we
just skipped there was a link to this
notebook and a QR code that link to this
notebook so um yeah so if anyone wants
to go to this notebook directly just do
your thing um cool um open the notebook
so recently I've been working on
introducing approximate nearest
neighbors to the e-commerce
search um and so with approximate
nearest neighbors how do you how you
typically do it you set the target hits
from the nearest neighbors operator uh
close or even bigger to the uh number of
hits you expect to get from the search
like the you expect to to get top 10
hits from from your search and for
approximate nearest neighbors you set
something like 100 so that you get
enough items to rank and then pick pick
the best but we had a bit of a different
approach we wanted to introduce
approximate nearest neighbors really
gently so we set Target hits way smaller
than the number of hits we wanted to
present on the page so we set Target
hits to one as as small as it gets and
the target hits were something more than
100 so what
happened um it was something unexpected
we got a a complaint from our user with
a with a video recording of our app that
um when he did a search he saw like Five
results on on the page and then we
applied the filter he received 500 plus
results like this should clearly not
happen you you restrict your search
results but then you get more hits it
was bad
so uh so of course we did some
investigation and the the the problem
uh boil down to the way that the search
is being executed in in inest oh I
forgot to say that this experiment was
done in um and it turned out that the
target hits is just a um lower bound of
how many hits you will get while asking
for nearest neighbors uh so what are the
other effects of doing the approximate
nearest neighbors with best
so this is the entire app
that tries to mimic the behavior that
we've
seen U the the important bit is probably
this one that that I'm I'm really not
into doing calculations mentally so my
vectors are just onedimensional so I
just put the number there so that the
distance meas is
nice and so
and later in the notebook I just do some
queries so if I do a query the nearest
neighbors with Target hits one and I put
this this Vector as as a as the only
query I get for some reason two
documents I asked for one I get two in
some other cases I get one document U
but that's that but if I change
the the query only
by changing the the query Vector
suddenly I get 10 hits that's that's a
bit unexpected so I I I played a bit
more
uh so so and here you see that I did
some exhaustive search on on with 100
queries and the amount of hits I got was
um uh was like kind of Mo most of the
time it was okay but for some queries it
was it was different it really depended
on the let's say the instance of of of
putting the documents into an index um
so um to summarize uh when you want to
gently introduce nearest neighbor search
into your application uh
like be um cautious that sometimes it
will give you something unexpected um
okay so that's it all thank you very
much that's all I thank
you thanks okay so we now have the bit
where we don't have to do any replugging
because it's going to be Daniel Wrigley
himself
presenting and he's he's perfectly ready
so Daniel go ahead yeah it's easy to be
perfectly ready if I'm not the first one
going on stage um or if I'm like the
20th person but I've been already 15 of
these persons the past two days so um
leveraging user Behavior insights from
evaluation to hybrid search optimization
we heard about the Ubi plug-in a couple
of times so Ubi is short for user
Behavior insights so there is a plug-in
out there um for open search that
enables you to collect user traffic um
but collecting user traffic is only the
first step so um we now want to take
that work one or maybe even two steps
further and actively use these signals
that we collect for that um we have two
rfc's open um at the moment an RFC if
you're not familiar with the open search
development uh process is like um a
suggestion to add something to the open
search world and the first RFC covers
the topic of
evaluation so in projects when we um
enter clients or enter client projects
we um always say so what is your query
set that you're measuring search quality
against and sometimes we don't hear
let's say a an answer that we want to
hear so we don't have a query set that
we can test on as user Behavior insights
collects all the queries that enter your
search system we can now use that data
as an input to create a query set based
on uh uh let's say a statistical
approach called probability proportional
to size sampling so that's a fancy name
for frequency weighted
sampling furthermore we want to uh
enable all open search users and uh U
data collectors to have an automated way
of calculating implicit judgments
so um you need a way to say this
document is a good match for this query
and we have a let's say surprising
number of customers who don't have any
judgments so enabling the search
Community to have an automated way of
not only collecting user Behavior data
but collecting judgments from these um
collected data is kind of um a second
Point here and last but not least we
want to use these implicit judgments to
then calculate search metric so that you
have a number that you can put next to
your search system and say um hey this
is how good it is at the moment and with
every Improvement that you ship this
number hopefully goes up at least if
it's a metric that needs to go up so if
you want to contribute to that RFC say
hey your ideas are rubbish I have a lot
of better ideas we'd like to hear them
so um please do participate in this RFC
if you want
to now only saying that um a system
scores in a specific way is like only
the starting point of an optimization
wheel so what we do in the optimization
part is um after we collect all the user
signals and calculate implicit
judgments we um propose what we call the
hybrid search Optimizer so it's a very
specific um let's say framework where we
want to um have an automated process
that um tries out all the different
combinations of parameters that are
connected to hybrid search in the open
search world because no one knows what
the best parameter set is for your
system so how should I wait keyword
search should I wait neuros search
should I use this combination technique
should I use that normalization
technique so there are a lot of
parameter
combinations and we want to prevent
everyone from going through all the
combinations manually and provide an
automatic way of doing so so the hybrid
search Optimizer figures out the best
hybrid search configuration for your
system offline you deploy it you measure
it in AB tests and then collect more
user signals and um off goes the um loop
again again another RFC um published two
days ago so we just made it uh in time
for the conference so if you want to
participate in that one as well feel
free to do so we want to hear all clever
ideas how we can solve that maybe in a
more efficient way than we are thinking
of um and um that's kind of it from my
side thanks thank you
Daniel okay so uh firstly I wanted to
say why uh there are two people it's not
like I have bipolar anything is uh my
colleague actually was the author of
this idea and I'm a mere present
so all the kudos to him he's on paternal
Le so double the Kudos and let me tell
you if oh the slide will change uh what
I'm going to shortly shortly um give you
the idea of his idea so we talked a lot
already about the runers at some point
and you probably heard about the thing
as goldbert and late interaction models
uh so usually when we work with runers
the best option you can take is cross
and coder which is very very heavy
because you use your query you use your
document you put them together in the
embedding model and then on the
inference time it will take very long
time which user probably wouldn't want
to wait even the answer is going to be
very very precise because you know like
in Hitchhiker's Guide you're not ready
to wait 100 years for 42 so people
always invent something they invented
later interaction models which you can
use offline and they are still much more
more precise as rankers because you can
um mostly repeat the same behavior as in
Cross encoder so you take your query you
embed it not as one vector you embed
each token of the query as one vector
and the same for the document you don't
try to push all the information from 100
pages into one vector you take each term
and it produces a vector so then you can
do all the
cross relationship between these terms
through the model which is called play
interaction right at the inference time
and this will produce pretty much more
um good results at the ranking point
because all the terms will interact with
each other so you know that the
similarity is more precise okay so what
is the idea usually everybody heard of
cobbert is pretty heavy you need to
store it you need to train it it trained
on a specific data set what if we're
just going to take any Ed embedding
model which is dense and use it as a
late interaction and it sounds like okay
what am I inventing here well let's uh
remind us what are all of these dance
embeddings models are doing what they
are so usually everything that is used
now is Transformers and they have this
architecture which I don't want to
explain it's like superale but the thing
is you throw in a sentence it's
dissected at tokens these tokens are at
the beginning of the way they don't know
what is next to them so you just take
every word separately but when it goes
through the model basically every
representation learns what is around it
what is the context and then at the end
each token which will be produced by the
tense model will know what is it
surrounded and then for example words
like amony like bat is going to actually
infusing them their meeting it's not
going to be like a bat for the baseball
the same as the bat which is like with
wings and usually what is done at the
end with these dense embedding models
they are pulled together into one vector
representation so they are either sumed
or they are maxed or they're weirdly
Twisted you know like um people at
research are very creative the thing is
well we usually have this part which is
then Twisted into one vector how about
we're not going to do any work we're
just going to take directly the
representation which our model produces
and use them in the same way the cold
bird is used in the late
interaction well idea is super simple
and you're like since when it's going to
work well it worked uh so we oh it's a
wrong one presentation but I love it
thank you so yeah that shouldn't be that
slide uh so what worked we uh did the
experiments on a beay data sets uh beay
data sets I probably you know that a lot
of model in the field are experimented
on a m Marco but it's better if you
train something so Colbert is trained on
a m Marco in many models usually they
are tested also on a m Marco and it's
not checking how the models work out of
the main so better if we go to bear and
we check on something more like you know
generalizable so we checked like Spate
all of the shiny new metal models split
colber and then we checked simple dance
models the small mini
lm6 which is used basically everywhere
and BG and as you can see with uh output
token EMB bances using them as late
interaction the quality increases this
is one data set this is another data set
well okay um why this experiment should
be interesting for
anybody firstly let's think about cost
Effectiveness um split cber these models
are considered more precise but they are
heavy they are very heavy when we are
talking about all mini LM BG they're
much much smaller So the faster is
inference but then the question is about
what about storage requirements because
Calbert outputs 128 sized embeddings
when all of these embedding models like
BGE I'll put something like 700 well
storage increases I don't want that
let's try to see what quantization is
going to do and the scar quantization is
actually not going to change anything
ndcg increas the quality um not
increasing sorry decreasing the quality
of basically nothing four times
decreases the memory so it takes less
than cobbert okay so we're not losing
anything with quantization we're
optimizing and it's working better how
can I try to use it because it still
maybe shouldn't be as effective as a
retriever and I would say that the
practical application that I would
advise you that we discovered is
actually a pretty optimal thing is all
of these models if you take them from
hug in PH they usually return this raw
output with tokens and then you apply
some poolings or they're there in the
Librarians don't throw away the r tokens
save them use this one vector the dance
Vector for initial Retriever and then
they use the late interaction one
version option for the Runing and then
the results are going to be actually
pretty impressive I mean of course I put
there that you can do it in query API
quadrant because I don't even have merch
so I had to to somehow affiliate myself
you know uh but the results are actually
pretty pretty good without creating
anything new without doing some new
architectures or whatever sometimes a
simple idea is something pretty
impressive and I need to say that uh in
any decen Vector database it should be
able to be done with basically two runs
two inferences with just like prefecture
and a runker at the same query so it's
our small recommendation for you guys
just a free advice and um I would like
to show this article it's called late
interaction models written by my
colleague and there are like a little
bit more details and in his GitHub you
can see the experiments where you could
rerun them and maybe take them and reuse
them and that's that's it very big thank
you thank you very
much hello hello hi almost the last one
so bear with me so I will be talking in
five minutes about how we use steps
driven Approach at he jobs for
search so going
right oops see all right so this is a
summarization of what Julian said
yesterday uh user Centric versus
business Centric so business people are
always behind revenue and does hurting a
precision and data scientist relevance
in Engineers or search Engineers always
run behind ndcg so all the talks you saw
it's all about ndcg and then there are
the real testers for us users this just
looking at the game we are playing
so one or one or more kind gets
frustrated because of the results
because of maybe the revenue generation
because of uh the ndcg metrics going
down so of course it demands a change
which Demands a changes in the query
changes in the architecture I won't go
into detail of that
but then it leads to offline testing and
AB testing and finalizing results so
many companies as far as I know does not
focus a lot on offline testing and what
we at Hobs try to do is focus more over
there so that we don't have to do the
iteration of making small change testing
it in a testing and again coming back so
this is the setup which we
follow so for relevance testing data
scientists and uh relevance Engineers
use Cupid thanks to open source
connections and we of course we have all
the data annotated we have people to
annotate that we know the queries which
we want to fix so as you can see we make
use of the snapshot feature and we
compare the query with current um the
new search query versus the current one
and yeah of course you can compare all
the other ranking metrics but this is
what we do for relevancy testing But
Here Comes the problem the search is not
always about relevancy testing it's also
the business people always wants
their um their listings held up so for
that we were not able to find any tool
so what we did is we just prepared a
tool internally for our own business
testing so what we do is similar to
Cupid we have our own static data we can
do this on production or QA and here
this is what we are trying to do is
compare the current search query with
the new search query and yeah means I
won't go into the settings but what we
have done is have created this tool to
have Dynamic where adjustment parameter
changes and all those things so what it
does it gives uh aggregated outlook for
the stakeholders product managers and
all to look into it how how the paid
listings look against the organic
listing against other kind of listing so
here you can see that okay in the
current side which is the left side and
the right side with the changes you see
that okay the distribution ch changes
maybe it's good for the business or bad
for the business and this is something
which they already come to know with
this there are more graphs for
this and what else this tool does is we
prepare also aggregated reports which
are also important for the marketing
teams because mostly the marketing team
Drive the campaigns through how we show
search results and then the most
important one is the relevance and
business tradeoff so through the report
we also show that how much relevancy
drops happens if we are pushing X
percentage of business items in the top
25 results so yeah exactly then we can
argue more strategically with product
managers that we don't want to hurt the
ndcg and this is U this is a good way to
convey the
results then yeah the last one is
documentation many people don't like
docum ing but what we do is for every
release proposed we have the whole
offline evaluation
documented the relevancy testing the
business evaluation everything so means
when even if the results even if the
test fails or passes we can rely back
and come back to this documentation and
this is the final one where users are
the one who would be approving this so
this is the a testing and of course we
use growth book The Open search Source
tool for a testing and if successful
everyone is happy data scientists
relevance Engineers users business yeah
that's it thank you